<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Articles on SELFSCRUM</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/</link><description>Recent content in Articles on SELFSCRUM</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Jam - build your own drop-in audio room</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/2021_03_27_jam/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/2021_03_27_jam/</guid><description>The first Clubhouse hype wave is over and now you can slowly think about what to do with this social media format and if there are good alternatives.
There are indeed. The other day I discovered on gitlab Jam that provides a very similar function as an open source system. These are single rooms that can be included as a service. I was too lazy this time to do the complete provisioning myself, so I took the hosting offer.</description></item><item><title>Lua Controller Programming</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/2021_03_08_luacontroller/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/2021_03_08_luacontroller/</guid><description>Lua controllers offer a great opportunity: you can program them in-game so that you can build systems, process events, and control switching outputs or other digital devices.
Lua controllers are, as the name suggests, programmed in Lua, which is the language in which Minetest itself is also largely written.
The controllers provide 4 inputs and outputs (port A to D).
The inputs can be reacted to via event control, the outputs can be set to true or false, i.</description></item><item><title>Don't lose track - the map of Minetest</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/2021_03_06_mapserver_mod/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/2021_03_06_mapserver_mod/</guid><description>Use the Mapserver Mod. If you play in Minetest, you will soon notice that the world is quite big. To be exact, 61839 * 61839 * 61839 nodes big. Thus, a discovery tour can become also sometimes an odyssey, if one does not find the way back any more.
The easiest way out is &amp;ldquo;to die&amp;rdquo;, because then you resurrect at the starting point of the game. This can be achieved, for example, by staying under water for a longer time or by crashing from a higher altitude while flying.</description></item><item><title>Minetest Server - (not quite) automatic setup</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/2021_02_27_minetest_setup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/2021_02_27_minetest_setup/</guid><description>As described recently, we are now using Minetest at school. To make the operation secure on the one hand, and stable and reasonably efficient on the other, we have opted for a (partially) automated solution. At Hetzner-Cloud, where we get cheap servers, the machine runs in a CX41 configuration. Data backup takes place in the Open Telekom Cloud, because there is inexpensive mass storage there for archiving purposes.
The installation itself is mostly automated, only the last 10% has to be done manually - mainly managing the keys and starting the configuration playbooks.</description></item><item><title>Home Office Video IT</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/2021_02_14_home_office_it/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/2021_02_14_home_office_it/</guid><description>The virtual workplace is quite real .
For me, the Corona period didn&amp;rsquo;t bring much new in terms of work - even before that I worked from home a lot, occasionally in video conferences, mostly via conference calls and screen sharing.
However, the boom of Zoom and comparable other systems like Teams, Jitsi, BigBlueButton has changed communication in the meantime. Only rarely do people still make phone calls, most of the time they chat right away via video call.</description></item><item><title>Minetest for our school</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/2021_02_08_minetest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/2021_02_08_minetest/</guid><description>Our own Minetest server .
We have discovered Minetest! The open source clone of the popular Minecraft game is great for recreating various aspects of the real world in school and thus learning in a playful and very individual way - as you can see on MinetestEducation, this has become an attractive place to go for many young people.
We want to run our own Minetest server, which will thus give us the opportunity not only to explore the game and the worlds within it, but also to further develop our digital concept.</description></item><item><title>Markdown vs MS Word</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/2020_10_10_markdown_vs_word/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/2020_10_10_markdown_vs_word/</guid><description>A Comparison .
When discussing Markdown, I hear often the &amp;ldquo;user acceptance&amp;rdquo; scepticism. Which is a pity since I think Markdown is actually easier than word. In my opinition,it is really necessary to get rid of the big office suites to get efficient processes, as I wrote here recently. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t use office apps, but not for tasks you better streamline.
Maybe this list helps to clarify the efficiency and acceptance perception ;)</description></item><item><title>Nextcloud hosted in Germany</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/2020_10_03_deploying-nextcloud/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/2020_10_03_deploying-nextcloud/</guid><description>Motivation .
Nextcloud as a communication solution is waiting in my backlog for a long time. Again and again something else came up - now I have a real use case. The Git for Kids Learning Circle has started for the first time and apart from zoom, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really have a communication platform yet. What could be more obvious than to finally test Nextcloud?
In view of the latest data protection legislation, it has also become clear once again that we have to move, we as consumers of the large platforms.</description></item><item><title>Git for Kids</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/gitforkids/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/gitforkids/</guid><description>Git More and more Markdown and Git are appearing outside the developer community.
Markdown is easy to learn by design, but Git is only understandable once the idea behind it has become clear and you have learned your options for the most common use cases. There are now many convenient tools for this purpose, but without knowing the basic principle, it remains hokey.
Learn Git Therefore the idea was born to create a learning circle that deals with the topic &amp;ldquo;Git learning&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Designing Digital Concept Workshops</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/workshop/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/workshop/</guid><description>We do not invent and test our concepts in a vacuum, but in connection with the development of the alternative school Freie Schule Ostfriesland. As we are about to expand the school for secondary schooling, there is a lot to think about and organise. In addition, due to fluctuation of active association members, some &amp;ldquo;onboarding activities&amp;rdquo; are pending, i.e. knowledge carriers disappear and new ones new introductions.
For this reason, we have arranged an all-day kick-off meeting with the concept team for the project this weekend, which should enable us to translate our high school vision into tangible work templates and guidelines.</description></item><item><title>Online workshops with yotribe.com</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/yotribe/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/yotribe/</guid><description>Spoiler: yotribe is new, slim and against all expectations very relaxed to use. The fact that it can currently be tested for free is an additional bonus.
How it starts The whole thing starts with an &amp;ldquo;application mail&amp;rdquo; from the provider. Not everyone is admitted immediately, you get on a waiting list with an alarmingly high waiting number. yotribe cunningly promises faster processing if you invite 3 friends as well. As a multi-account holder no problem - 2-3 days later comes the redeeming start link.</description></item><item><title>Community has opened</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/community/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/community/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;It takes a village to raise a child&amp;rdquo; - and a community to create a project.
According to this motto we are now one step further in education - since the beginning of the week our Online Community is up and running, which was founded with the aim to make SELFSCRUM an open operating system for open learning. It&amp;rsquo;s quite an extension of the original idea, which was obviously focused on the use of software.</description></item><item><title>Automated Multi-Format Publishing with Github</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/docproduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/docproduction/</guid><description>Motivation and features An arduous task in the production of content is the provision of different document formats. Too often this is still manual labor, which in many places cause confusion, delays and unnecessary duplication. I always wanted to change this, and now it&amp;rsquo;s about time. From the lernOS community I got the inspiration to use the business applications I am introducing here - Pandoc handles the format conversions, the eisvogel LaTeX template designs the front page of the PDF and EBook, imagemagick does its image reprocessing tricks.</description></item><item><title>lernOS</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/lernos/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/lernos/</guid><description>We have already discussed use cases and also some processes for our emerging platform and created an MVP from these. What I was still missing as a starting point for the implementation: a management concept that fits to our ideas and that can be flexibly adapted to our needs. Scrum classic is too heavy and too nerdy for students, and we have different cycles compared to a normal software development project.</description></item><item><title>Finalist!</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/finalist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/finalist/</guid><description>We are happy and proud that we have been named finalist today :)
Our submission video is here!</description></item><item><title>Selfscrum - What is it?</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/whatisit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/whatisit/</guid><description>First definition of SELFSCRUM, created during the hackathon. In the meantime we have developed quite a bit, see About Us.
During the #EUvsVirus hackathon or when talking with friends about my new passion project, I more often than not get the blank stare in the face of my coutnerpart that signals me that I got lost in space, and not everyone else. So I will try to explain here what Selfscrum is and how we are planning to do good in the world of schooling or, better, learning (which are not synonyms.</description></item><item><title>Submission</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/submission/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/submission/</guid><description>It was not easy to crawl out of bed this morning. And the start of our little project is tough, we circle around different options how to proceed. After the first break, Rogerio creates the breakthrough by asking to work for himself. This terminates the peer pressure and everyone can start creating the assets he or she can do best. We now quickly develop the pattern how to work proceses, how the screens should loke like for them, and how the overall assembly can work.</description></item><item><title>MVP</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/mvp/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/mvp/</guid><description>Some machinery got upset yesterday by the temporary breakdown of the hackathon submission system - we got notice that the first checkin point of our mentor is not 10am but 2pm. Also fine, leaves some more time for breakfast and morning coffee. We start in the late morning, team increased by Ümran who brought a friend.
The start is slow but we gain momentum. Théo our interaction design expert conjures up diagram after diagram, and some really helpful templates.</description></item><item><title>Kickoff</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/kickoff/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/kickoff/</guid><description>Wow what a kickoff :) 5 members are in the team - Annie from UK, Ümmühan from Turkey, Théo from France and Rogerio from Portugal appeared one after the other in the video meeting which became an icon so quick in these times. 5 countries, 3 timezones, no pre-approved business plan nor a motivational speech - and yet we managed after a short intrductionary round to jump right into the topic of our hackathon project - solidifying and extending the inital idea of a &amp;ldquo;programmed whiteboard&amp;rdquo; that allows students and their mates, mentors, and parents, to collaborate or at least participate in the student&amp;rsquo;s learn path.</description></item><item><title>How it all begins</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/post1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/post1/</guid><description>Inspiration We founded an open school two years ago, and educate students how to plan their learning paths, which they have to do themselves in our school. Since we don&amp;rsquo;t prescribe any formal curriculum, and don&amp;rsquo;t do tests or assessments, most of the existing management school software is not usable for us. This is especially true in the current situation where pupils have to stay home.
We think that the learner is the owner of his/her learning path, and as such has to have the possibilty to learn how to manage it.</description></item></channel></rss>