<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on SELFSCRUM</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/page/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on SELFSCRUM</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 13:18:45 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.selfscrum.org/en/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About Us</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/page/about-selfscrum/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 13:18:45 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/page/about-selfscrum/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="what-is-selfscrum">What is SELFSCRUM?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Very simple - SELFSCRUM is an open source operating system for open democratic schools.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What does that mean? I think we need a united effort from all parties involved to take child and youth learning to a new level that is appropriate for today and for the great challenges of the future. I am firmly convinced that school and learning must be completely rethought.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The good news is that there are already many good approaches. They come from many different directions. Be it from classical schools, where many motivated people with good ideas try to keep a frozen system alive, be it from the free economy, where knowledge and learning are essential for survival today, and also from the worldwide open source community, where much is shared and developed without commercial interest. And last but not least, the social forces of the current sustainability movements, who have learned to organize themselves in a modern way to give their concerns a voice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like any complex system, such a structure is not created overnight and not in the quiet chamber of a tinkerer. Hence this community as a starting point for a hopefully lively and diverse development with a stable core.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Imprint &amp; Privacy</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/page/privacy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 13:18:45 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/page/privacy/</guid><description>IMPRINT Information according to § 5 TMG Website owner:
Martin Jahr Blücherstraße 14 26603 Aurich Contact Phone: +49 (0) 170 371 66 36 E-Mail: info &amp;ldquo;@&amp;rdquo; selfscrum.org Note on the Website Site Design: Martin Jahr All Images: Martin Jahr PRIVACY Privacy at a glance General notes The following notes provide a simple overview of what happens to your personal data when you visit our website.</description></item></channel></rss>