<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Minetest on SELFSCRUM</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/categories/minetest/</link><description>Recent content in Minetest on SELFSCRUM</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.selfscrum.org/en/categories/minetest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lua Controller Programming</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/2021_03_08_luacontroller/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/2021_03_08_luacontroller/</guid><description>Lua controllers offer a great opportunity: you can program them in-game so that you can build systems, process events, and control switching outputs or other digital devices.
Lua controllers are, as the name suggests, programmed in Lua, which is the language in which Minetest itself is also largely written.
The controllers provide 4 inputs and outputs (port A to D).
The inputs can be reacted to via event control, the outputs can be set to true or false, i.</description></item><item><title>Don't lose track - the map of Minetest</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/2021_03_06_mapserver_mod/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/2021_03_06_mapserver_mod/</guid><description>Use the Mapserver Mod. If you play in Minetest, you will soon notice that the world is quite big. To be exact, 61839 * 61839 * 61839 nodes big. Thus, a discovery tour can become also sometimes an odyssey, if one does not find the way back any more.
The easiest way out is &amp;ldquo;to die&amp;rdquo;, because then you resurrect at the starting point of the game. This can be achieved, for example, by staying under water for a longer time or by crashing from a higher altitude while flying.</description></item><item><title>Minetest Server - (not quite) automatic setup</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/2021_02_27_minetest_setup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/2021_02_27_minetest_setup/</guid><description>As described recently, we are now using Minetest at school. To make the operation secure on the one hand, and stable and reasonably efficient on the other, we have opted for a (partially) automated solution. At Hetzner-Cloud, where we get cheap servers, the machine runs in a CX41 configuration. Data backup takes place in the Open Telekom Cloud, because there is inexpensive mass storage there for archiving purposes.
The installation itself is mostly automated, only the last 10% has to be done manually - mainly managing the keys and starting the configuration playbooks.</description></item><item><title>Minetest for our school</title><link>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/2021_02_08_minetest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selfscrum.org/en/article/2021_02_08_minetest/</guid><description>Our own Minetest server .
We have discovered Minetest! The open source clone of the popular Minecraft game is great for recreating various aspects of the real world in school and thus learning in a playful and very individual way - as you can see on MinetestEducation, this has become an attractive place to go for many young people.
We want to run our own Minetest server, which will thus give us the opportunity not only to explore the game and the worlds within it, but also to further develop our digital concept.</description></item></channel></rss>